export const CHRISTIANRELIGIOUSSTUDIESA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The caravan of Ishmaelites, that bought Joseph, traded in ________",
A: "Balm, gum and myrrh",
B: "Oil, balm and gum",
C: "Myrrh, maize and wheat",
D: "Gum, frank incense and oil",
answer: "A. Balm, gum and myrrh",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Before Joseph came to Pharaoh after his release from prison, Joseph ________",
A: "Ate some food",
B: "Prayed fervently",
C: "Shaved and ate",
D: "Shaved and changed his clothes",
answer: "D. Shaved and changed his clothes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. How long was the famine before Joseph reconciled with his brothers? they met Joseph",
A: "1 year",
B: "2 years",
C: "4 years",
D: "5 years",
answer: "B. 2 years",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following was not an excuse Moses gave when he was called to deliver the Israelites?",
A: "The Israelites would not believe him",
B: "He was slow to speak",
C: "He was a murderer",
D: "He doubted his own ability",
answer: "C. He was a murderer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Regardless of the Egyptians’ suffering, Pharaoh refused to let the Israelites go because _______",
A: "The Israelites gave them cheap labour",
B: "Pharaoh wanted to challenge God",
C: "God allowed the Israelites to suffer",
D: "The Israelites refused to pray to God",
answer: "A. The Israelites gave them cheap labour",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A soon as the Egyptians caught up with the Israelites at the Red sea, the pillar of clouds _______",
A: "Vanished from the sight of the Israelites",
B: "Stood on the left side of the Israelites",
C: "Stood between the Israelites and the Egyptians",
D: "Moved ahead of the Israelites",
answer: "C. Stood between the Israelites and the Egyptians",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. One of the spies Moses sent to the land of Canaan from the tribe of Reuben was ________",
A: "Shaphat",
B: "Shammua",
C: "Igal",
D: "Gaddiel",
answer: "D. Gaddiel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Why does the Lord bring us into this land, to fall by the sword? Our wives and our little ones will become a prey; ________ on which occasion was this statement made? When the ________",
A: "Israelites got to the Red sea",
B: "Israelites had no water to drink",
C: "Spies gave adverse report",
D: "Egyptians caught up with the Israelites",
answer: "C. Spies gave adverse report",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Barak who was asked by Deborah to organize troops to fight the Canaanites was the son of ___________",
A: "Joab",
B: "Jehoahaz",
C: "Abijah",
D: "Abinoam",
answer: "D. Abinoam",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. You shall invest him with some of your authority, that all the congregation of the people of Israel may obey. This instruction was given in connection with the ___________",
A: "Appointment of Joshua to succeed Moses",
B: "Appointment of Eleazar as priest to succeed Aaron",
C: "Appointment of Aaron as Moses’ spokesman",
D: "Election of Eleazar by Aaron to succeed him",
answer: "A. Appointment of Joshua to succeed Moses",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Why do you do such thing? For I hear of your evil dealings from all the people. No my sons; it is no good report that I hear ……. The sons being addressed were children of _________",
A: "Joshua",
B: "Samuel",
C: "Elkannah",
D: "Eli",
answer: "D. Eli",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. At the time Samuel was ministering to the Lord under Eli, _______",
A: "There were many prophets in Israel",
B: "The word of God was rare with no frequent vision",
C: "Idolatry was common in Israel",
D: "Visions were used by God to give directions",
answer: "B. The word of God was rare with no frequent vision",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Through meditation, the book of the law became Joshua’s source of _______",
A: "Justice and freedom",
B: "Peace and harmony",
C: "Prosperity and success",
D: "Courage and strength",
answer: "C. Prosperity and success",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Israel lost 30,000 soldiers in a battle with the Philistine because _____",
A: "The Ark of God was captured",
B: "The soldiers disobeyed God",
C: "Of the sins of Eli’s sons",
D: "Of the absence of Eli at the battle field",
answer: "C. Of the sins of Eli’s sons",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The reaction of Saul’s armour-bearer after the death of his master amounted to _________",
A: "Faithfulness",
B: "Bravery",
C: "Disappointment",
D: "Loyalty",
answer: "D. Loyalty",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. When David and Abishai went to the camp of Saul at Ziph, Saul and his men were fast asleep because ____________",
A: "They were very tired due to the hard day’s work",
B: "They wanted David to kill Saul and his men",
C: "They were afraid of their enemies so they slept in a cave",
D: "The Lord allowed a deep sleep to fall on them",
answer: "D. The Lord allowed a deep sleep to fall on them",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The child David had with Uri’ah’s wife fell sick and died within _____",
A: "Seven days",
B: "Eight days",
C: "Nine days",
D: "Ten days",
answer: "A. Seven days",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. After Solomon had the dream at Gibeon, the Lord promised to lengthen his days on condition that he would ______",
A: "Sacrifice to him",
B: "Pray daily",
C: "Offer burnt offering",
D: "Walk in his ways",
answer: "D. Walk in his ways",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The King of Tyre who supported King Solomon with timber for the building of the temple was ________",
A: "Hiram",
B: "Neco",
C: "Dairus",
D: "Cyrus",
answer: "A. Hiram",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. God decided not to divide the kingdom of Israel during the reign of Solomon because_________",
A: "Solomon built the temple for God",
B: "Solomon was a very wise king",
C: "Of God’s love for David",
D: "Of Israel’s repentance",
answer: "C. Of God’s love for David",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The kingdom of Israel was divided during the reign of Rehoboam because, he _______",
A: "Followed his father’s tyranny",
B: "Led Israel to war",
C: "Challenged Jeroboam I",
D: "Worshipped other gods",
answer: "A. Followed his father’s tyranny",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Yes what they are building if a fox goes up on it he will break down their stone wall! This remark made by Tobiah was intended to _______",
A: "Alert and encourage Nehemiah",
B: "Stop and disgrace the Jews",
C: "Embarrass Nehemiah",
D: "Ridicule the Jews",
answer: "D. Ridicule the Jews",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following people led the rebuilding of the temple in Jerusalem after the Jews returned from exile?",
A: "Sheatiel and Zechariah",
B: "Jeshua and Haggai",
C: "Haggai and Zechariah",
D: "Zerubbabel and Jeshua",
answer: "D. Zerubbabel and Jeshua",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Two kings of Persia who passed decrees to bring about the rebuilding of the temple in Jerusalem were _________",
A: "Cyrus and Belshazzar",
B: "Darius and Cyrus",
C: "Haggai and Belshazzar",
D: "Artaxerxes and Nebuchadnezzar",
answer: "B. Darius and Cyrus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The Jew who came from exile to Jerusalem to study the law of the Lord and teach others was _________",
A: "Sheshbazzar",
B: "Haggai",
C: "Zechariah",
D: "Ezra",
answer: "D. Ezra",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. According to Luke’s gospel, when the Devil had ended the temptation of Jesus, the Devil departed _______",
A: "and Jesus was baptized in the Jordan",
B: "to work out a better strategy",
C: "feeling defeated and embarrassed",
D: "and Angels came to minister to Jesus because He had accomplished His mission",
answer: "B. to work out a better strategy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Jesus stood in a boat belonging to Peter by the lake of Gennesaret to ________",
A: "heal the sick",
B: "cure the leper",
C: "raise the dead",
D: "teach the crowd",
answer: "D. teach the crowd",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The gospel which states that the spirit immediately drove Jesus into the wilderness after His baptism to be tempted is _________",
A: "Mark’s gospel",
B: "Luke’s gospel",
C: "John’s gospel",
D: "Matthew’s gospel",
answer: "D. Matthew’s gospel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. According to Mark’s gospel, Jesus was baptized by John the Baptist after He came from _________",
A: "Capernaum",
B: "Judea",
C: "Nazareth",
D: "Bethlehem",
answer: "C. Nazareth",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. What was Jesus’ response to the would be disciple who wanted to bury his father?",
A: "Foxes have wholes and birds have nests",
B: "He could go and give his father a befitting burial",
C: "Follow me and let your siblings bury him",
D: "Follow me and leave the dead to bury their own dead",
answer: "D. Follow me and leave the dead to bury their own dead",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. My soul is very sorrowful, even to death, remain here and watch with me…. Jesus made this statement to _______",
A: "Peter, James and John",
B: "The seventy disciples",
C: "The twelve apostles",
D: "Andrew, James and Stephen",
answer: "A. Peter, James and John",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. According to Jesus, a major condition for discipleship is to _______",
A: "be baptized with immersion",
B: "Overcome all temptations",
C: "Respect parents and elderly people",
D: "Renounce all that one has",
answer: "D. Renounce all that one has",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Peter wept after he had denied Jesus because he was ________",
A: "Sad since Jesus was going to be killed",
B: "Going to miss Jesus",
C: "Recognized as Jesus’ disciple",
D: "Feeling ashamed for the betrayal",
answer: "D. Feeling ashamed for the betrayal",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Have you come out as a robber with swords and clubs to capture me? This statement was said by Jesus _______",
A: "In the garden of Gethsemane",
B: "During HIs trial",
C: "During His crucifixion",
D: "At Golgotha on the cross",
answer: "A. In the garden of Gethsemane",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Jesus’ enemies accused him of perverting the nation, forbidding the payment of tribute to Ceaser and claiming to be a King before ________",
A: "Herod",
B: "The High Priest",
C: "Pilate",
D: "The Sanhedrin",
answer: "C. Pilate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. What prompted Pilate to send Jesus to Herod for trial? Pilate _______",
A: "Realized that Jesus was innocent",
B: "Knew Jesus came from Herod’s jurisdiction",
C: "Wanted to avoid being blamed for Jesus’ death",
D: "Saw that Herod was a better judge",
answer: "B. Knew Jesus came from Herod’s jurisdiction",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The women who visited the tomb of Jesus on the first day according to Luke’s gospel were ________",
A: "Mary Magdalene, Joana and Mary the mother of James",
B: "Joana, Salome and Mary the mother of Jesus",
C: "Salome, Eunice and Mary Magdalene",
D: "Mary the mother of James, Salome and Joana",
answer: "A. Mary Magdalene, Joana and Mary the mother of James",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. What punishment was given to the unmerciful servant by the King in Jesus’ teaching on forgiveness?",
A: "He was demoted",
B: "He was killed",
C: "His family was sold",
D: "He was imprisoned",
answer: "D. He was imprisoned",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Judas Iscariot lost his position as a disciple of Jesus because he _______",
A: "Was expelled",
B: "Fell sick and died",
C: "Committed suicide",
D: "Denounced the faith",
answer: "C. Committed suicide",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. When Peter and John were set free by the Sanhedrin, they were ______",
A: "Asked not to speak about Jesus again",
B: "Asked to join the other apostles",
C: "Given thirty-nine lashes each",
D: "Sent to Pilate for trial",
answer: "A. Asked not to speak about Jesus again",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Why did you go to uncircumcised men and eat with them? The uncircumcised men in the context were ________",
A: "Sanhedrin and the Pharisees",
B: "Aeneas and his family",
C: "Saul and his friends",
D: "Cornelius and his family",
answer: "D. Cornelius and his family",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. But be doers of the word not hearers only. This text according to James implies that Christians should _______",
A: "Reflect their faith in their lifestyles",
B: "Live above reproach and wickedness",
C: "Love one another as Christ did",
D: "Set heaven as their goal to achieve",
answer: "A. Reflect their faith in their lifestyles",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Discrimination in the daily distribution of relief items in the early church came up when the _________",
A: "Hellenists complained about neglect of their widows",
B: "Hebrews complained about neglect of their widows",
C: "Apostles refused to serve tables",
D: "Apostles decided to appoint deacons",
answer: "A. Hellenists complained about neglect of their widows",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. What happened to Saul while in the house of Judas in the street called Straight?",
A: "An attempt to be lynched for betraying Judaism",
B: "An attempt to be killed for opposing the gospel",
C: "His escape to Jerusalem through Barnabas",
D: "The regaining of his sight through Ananias",
answer: "D. The regaining of his sight through Ananias",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Herod Agrippa’s killing of James and subsequent arrest of Peter was an attempt to _________",
A: "Demonstrate his hatred for Christians",
B: "Fulfill the order of the Roman Emperor",
C: "Win the confidence of the Jews",
D: "Show how powerful he was",
answer: "C. Win the confidence of the Jews",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. James states that the sick should be interceded for by the Elders but those who are suffering should _________",
A: "Fast daily",
B: "Go to Church",
C: "Read the Bible",
D: "Pray themselves",
answer: "D. Pray themselves",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. In his teaching on faith and works, James says that people should be quick to hear, slow to speak and _________",
A: "Be fervent in prayer",
B: "Be involved in fasting",
C: "Slow to fight",
D: "Slow to anger",
answer: "D. Slow to anger",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Peter holds the view that servants should be submissive and be respectful to masters who are good and gentle as well as to those who are ________",
A: "God fearing",
B: "Older than item",
C: "Overbearing",
D: "Arrogant",
answer: "A. God fearing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Peter is of the opinion that Christians should behave like new born babies craving for pure spiritual milk so that ________",
A: "They will have salvation",
B: "They can be loved by the Lord",
C: "The Lord will deliver them",
D: "The Lord will provide for them",
answer: "A. They will have salvation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Peter advised the leaders of the church not to lord their eldership over their members but should rather _________",
A: "Pray for them regularly",
B: "Visit them regularly",
C: "Lead them with good example",
D: "Provide their needs",
answer: "C. Lead them with good example",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]